theapplicantmanager.com 2017-04-06

# The Applicant Manager | Applicant Tracking System | Recruiting Software | TAM

**This Privacy Policy is effective as of February 15, 2014.**

This policy covers the website at http://www.theapplicantmanager.com (the "Site") and explains our information practices, data security practices, defines your privacy options and describes how your information is collected and used by The Applicant Manager ("TAM", "we", or "us"). 

By using this Site, you agree to the collection and use of information in the manner described by this policy. We shall have the right at any time and without prior notice, at our sole discretion, to revise this policy. Such revisions and additions shall be effective immediately upon notice, which may be given by any means, including but not limited to posting the revised or additional terms and conditions on this Site. You are responsible for reviewing the Site periodically for any modification to this policy. 

**Personal Information we Collect**

This policy applies to all information collected on this Site and any information you provide to us as a client of TAM. In addition, it applies to any applicants who provide resumes, cover letters, references, applications for employment, or any other information when applying for positions with our clients. 

You can generally visit the Site without revealing any personally identifiable information about yourself. We do not collect personal information from our Site visitors without the Site visitor providing us with this information as set forth in this Privacy Policy. 

If you wish to receive company or product information or request an online demonstration of the Services, you can do so by completing the online demo request form on our Site that asks for your name, company name, e-mail address, and phone number. You can also voluntarily provide comments to us when submitting the request form. We use the information from the request form to deliver the requested information and/or provide you with an online demonstration of TAM. 

In order to become a registered user of TAM, we require you to create a user account. Information we collect to register a user account will include, but is not limited to, the following personally identifiable information: first and last name, user name, password, and email address. The personal information we collect on behalf of our clients from our clients’ applicants will be dictated by our clients as they configure online employment applications. 

**Non-Personal Information we may Collect**

In addition to the personal information you supply, we may collect certain information to evaluate how visitors use our Site. We collect data to make our service work better for you by improving the design of the Site, by providing personalization of the Site and to evaluate the performance of our marketing programs. The technologies we use to gather this non-personal information may include IP addresses, cookies, clear gifs, browser detection, and weblogs. We further use this information to provide a better experience on our website and to give us useful business information. 

"IP" addresses define the Internet location of computers and help us better understand the geographic distribution of our members and manage the performance of the Site. "Cookies" are tiny files placed onto the hard drive of your computer when you visit the Site, so we can immediately recognize you when you return to the site and deliver content specific to your interests. You may modify your browser preferences to accept all cookies, be notified when a cookie is set, or reject all cookies. Please consult your browser instructions for information on how to modify your choices about cookies. 

We may also use a technology called "clear gifs". Clear gifs are tiny graphics with unique identifiers that are used to track emails and online movements, helping us understand what marketing campaigns and content are effective. 

We may detect the type of web browser you are using to optimize the performance of our website and to understand the mix of browsers used by our clients and visitors. To learn about how people use our site, we examine weblogs, which show the paths people take through our site and how long they spend in certain areas. We may also track and analyze non-identifying and aggregate usage and volume statistical information from our visitors and clients. 

**How we use Information**

Our primary goal in collecting your client information is to provide you with a personalized, relevant, and positive experience with the Site. We use the information that we collect to set up Services for individuals and their organizations. We may also use the information to contact clients to further discuss client interest in our company, the Services that we provide, and to send information regarding our company or partners, such as promotions and events. 

TAM collects information under the direction of its clients, and has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. Client email addresses and any personal client information will not be distributed or shared with any third parties. We may email information regarding updates to the Service. Except as we explicitly state at the time we request information, or as provided for in the TAM Terms of Use, we do not disclose to any third-party the information provided. 

**Choice and Access to Data Controlled by our Clients**

TAM has no direct relationship with the individual employees and job-seekers whose personal data it processes on behalf of our clients. Individuals applying for jobs with employers that are TAM clients can contact the employers directly to correct, amend, and delete inaccurate data provided to the employer as part of the online application process. The employer is responsible for complying with the individual’s request. In accordance with applicable law, TAM retains an archive copy of the individual’s data for the period prescribed by such law. Additionally, if you are an employee or job-seeker and would no longer like to be contacted by a particular employer or employers, please contact them directly to resolve your concern. 

**Updating, Correcting and Deleting Your Information**

TAM provides an individual that supplies information on the Site with the ability to review, correct, and request the deletion of any of the personally identifiable information that was entered into their profile on the Site. To correct or delete any information in a Site profile, an individual may update that profile (through their account page on the Site) or may contact TAM by e-mailing our client support at support@theapplicantmanager.com. We will respond to the request within 30 days. Alternatively, you may send a letter with your requested changes, corrections or deletions to the following mailing address: 

The HR Manager, LLC  
Attn: Privacy Policy  
369-B 3rd Street, Suite 655  
San Rafael, CA 94901 

When a client terminates their account on the Site, we will deactivate their profile from the Site. Information supplied by an employee or job seeker in an application or resume submitted to an employer that is a TAM client is treated as described above in the section "Choice and Access to Data Controlled by our Clients." 

**Data Security**

The security of your personal information is important to us. We follow industry-standard technical and organizational measures to protect the security of our users' and applicants' personal information. Our site is hosted on secure, fire-walled servers. We use 256-bit SSL (Secure Socket Layer) encryption for all data transfers. Access to our clients' data is controlled by user names and passwords, both of which are further encrypted by a complex hashing routine. Clients are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality and security of their user names and passwords. All client data is backed up daily. Only authorized TAM employees have access to clients' data and we never share that data with other clients. 

However, TAM cannot guarantee that unauthorized third parties will never be able to defeat these measures or use your personally identifiable information for improper purposes. Therefore, you should be aware that when you voluntarily display or distribute personally identifiable information, that information could be collected and used by others. TAM is not responsible for the unauthorized use by third parties of information you post or otherwise make available publicly. 

**Communications with our clients / Opt-Out Preferences**

When you sign up as a registered TAM user, you may elect to have TAM provide you with marketing communications such as e-mail newsletters, product and service updates and promotions. Our clients generally find this type of information useful. If you do not want to continue to receive such communications, you can select the "unsubscribe" link at the bottom of any marketing communication email and follow the opt-out instructions. 

**TAM Service Providers**

We engage certain trusted third parties to perform functions and provide services to us, including, without limitation, website hosting and maintenance, client relationship management, database storage and management, and direct marketing campaigns. We will share your personally identifiable information with these third parties, but only to the extent necessary to perform these functions and provide such services, and only pursuant to binding contractual obligations requiring such third parties to maintain the privacy and security of your data. 

**Disclosure of Information**

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information: (a) if we are required to do so by law, regulation or other government authority or otherwise in cooperation with an investigation of a governmental authority, and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order or legal process (b) to enforce the TAM Terms of Use or Master Subscription Agreement or (c) to protect our rights and the safety of users of our Site and our Services. It is also possible that TAM would sell all or substantially all of its assets and business. In any transaction of this kind, client information, including your personally identifiable information, may be among the assets that are transferred. If we decide to so transfer your personally identifiable information, you will be notified by email. 

**Link to Other Websites**

The Site may contain links to other websites. TAM is not responsible for the privacy practices of these other sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site, and to read the privacy statements of each web site that collects personally identifiable information. Some linked sites may be co-branded with our trademarks and those of our business partners. This policy only applies to information collected by TAM. 

**U.S.-EU Safe Harbor**

The HR Manager LLC complies with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland. The HR Manager LLC has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view our certification, please visit http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/ 

**How to Contact Us**

Should you have privacy questions or concerns, please call us at 855-254-1277, send an email to info@thehrmanager.com, or snail mail to The HR Manager, 369-B 3rd St, Suite 655, San Rafael, CA 94901.
